# **SULAIMAN MUSTAPHA MAYOWA**

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Enthusiastic and energetic graduate of business administration blends academic training with hands on experience in financial analysis, presentations and copywriting work to perform daily financial responsibilities with accuracy and thoroughness. Excel as an individual contributor and in collaborative team settings, delivery task on time and to specification.

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

Sex: Male

Contact Address: Sw5/183, Oshoba Street, Agbokojo Area, Oke Ado, Ibadan

**Telephone:** 09062222013.

**E-mail:** sulaimanmustapha1807@gmail.com

**D.O.B: 1**8th July,1987

## **EDUCATION QUALIFICATION**

• Graduate Diploma: Business Management, 2015

Nigerian Institute of Management (Chartered) (NIM), Lagos.

• Bachelor of Science: Business Administration(Hons), 2014

With Second Lower Class (Degree)

University of Abuja, Mini Campus, Gwagwalada, Federal Capital Territory, Abuja.

• **Diploma Certificate:** Business Administration, 2010

University of Abuja, Mini Campus, Gwagwalada, Federal Capital Territory, Abuja.

• Certificate: Computer Training, 2006

Rakfa Computer Institute, St. James Cathedral Shopping Complex, Oke Bola, Ibadan.

• West African Examination Council: WAEC, 2004

I.M.G. Grammar School, Sharp Corner, Oke Ado, Ibadan, Oyo State.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

ICSL/Stanbic IBTC Bank, Agodi Gate Branch, Ibadan.

January 2019 - Date

#### Marketer (Business Banking)

- Identify and understand the needs of the Customers
- Ensure Customer profile falls within focus segment i.e. Blue, Silver or SME.
- Sell the Banks Products proactively to new/prospective customers.
- Obtain relevant documents on all Bank products sold, e.g. identity document, business registration documents etc.
- Ensure accuracy of all bank forms and documents executed by the Customer.
- Ensure timely processing of all initiated Customer transactions, with specific emphasis on account opening, ATM card and cheque book issuance.
- Ensure assigned sales target and budgets are met.

# Mutual Benefit Life Assurance, Regional Office, Ibadan.

#### October 2018 - December 2018

## **Marketing Executive**

- Design and implement effective marketing strategies to sell new insurance contract or adjust existing ones.
- Contact potential clients and create rapport by networking, cold calling, and using referral.
- Appraise the wishes and demands of business or individual customers and sell the suitable protection plans
- Collect information from clients on their risk profiles in order to offer them the proper solution.
- Retain continuous awareness of transactions, sales and terms and keep relative records.

# Gamji Nigeria Company Limited, Abuja.

#### February 2017 - June 2018

#### Administrative officer

- Resolve administrative problems by preparing reports and analyzing data.
- Delivered exceptional customer service to clients.
- Creates and submits financial reports as needed.
- Handle petty cash, floats and expenses.
- Obtained signatures for financial documents, and internal and external invoices.
- Serve as corporate liaison between the finance and marketing departments.
- Conduct risk assessment of all departments.
- Evaluate regulatory compliance programs

# Andy Ventures, (Coca Cola Depot), Bauchi State.

## March 2016 - January 2017

# **Accounting Clerk**

- Perform accounting and clerical functions to support manager.
- Issue checks for accounts payable.
- Work with adding machines, calculators, databases and bank accounts.
- Utilize computer systems to run databases, pay bills and order supplies.
- Input type vouchers, invoices, checks, account statements, reports, and other records.
- Provide front desk customer service.

# The Zion Place College, Ijegun/Ijagemo Road, Lagos.

## October 2014 - July 2015

## **Educator (NYSC)**

- Taught Financial Accounting, Economics and Business studies.
- Conducting in class activities.

• Organize career talk for the students.

# Darlington Palace Hotel, Darlington Street, Mokola, Ibadan.

November 2013 - July 2014

#### Manager

- Planning maintenance work, events and room bookings.
- Handling customer complaints and queries.
- Recruiting, training and supervising staffs
- Promoting and marketing the business.
- Maintaining budgets.

# T.I.A Investment, 5, Adetayo Osho Street, Akoka, Lagos.

October 2005 - June 2017

## Office Clerk

- Compile, copy, sort, and file records of office activities, business transactions, and other activities.
- Operate office machines, such as photocopiers and scanners, and desktop computer.
- Deliver messages and run errand
- Process and prepare documents, such as business or government forms and expense reports.
- Answer telephones, direct calls and take messages.
- Communicate with customers, to answer questions, take orders and address complaints.

# **SKILLS**

Excellent communication and presentation skills.

Analytical thinking, sound judgements and decision-making.

Knowledge of accounting principles and databases.

Customer service oriented.

Computer competences.

Ability to work under moderate pressure.

Strong attention to details.

Excellent team work attitude and target oriented.

Interpersonal skills and self motivated.

# **INTEREST**

Teaching, Reading, Travelling, Football, Team dynamics and Networking